Register of the Haig Shekerjian Papers, 1905-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
Haig Shekerjian Papers,
1905-1966
72081
Shekerjian, Haig
4 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (1.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, notes, speeches, and medals, relating to American chemical warfare activities during World War II
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1972.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Shekerjian, Haig, 1886-1966
1886, 13 June Born, Turkey
1906 Student, Colgate University
1907 Entered military service as a cadet
1911 Graduate, B.S. degree and commissioned as second lieutenant of Infantry
1916-17 Served with the Punitive Expedition in Mexico under General Pershing
1914-1918 Assistant military attaché in Greece, with the Allied Armies of the Orient in the Middle East
1923 Transferred to the Chemical Warfare Service
1942 Promoted to Brigadier General
1939-1945 Chemical Officer, First Army; Commanding General of the Chemical Warfare Replacement Center; Commanding General at Camp Sibert, Alabama
1946 Retired from military service
1966 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, notes, speeches, and medals, relating to American chemical warfare activities during World War II
Access Points
United States.--Army--Officers; Chemical warfare; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Chemical warfare; United States--Armed Forces
Container List
- Correspondence, 1926-1964. (Box Box No. 1.)
  Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Ahmed Abboud Pasha 1945 (Box 1.)
  - Almond, E.M. (Brigadier General) 1942
  - Assistant Secretary of State 1946
  - Bain, William J. 1946
  - Brees, H.J. (Lt. General) 1940
  - Brigham, C.E. (Major General) 1936
  - Chamberlain, Fred V.S. 1926
  - Chipman, Mrs. Guy W.
  - Craig, Mr. 1941
  - Eisenhower, Dwight 1955
  - Gantengein, Mrs. James
  - Guggenheim, Robert (Colonel) 1946
  - Gullion, Allen W. 1942
  - Hanford, Ned 1940
  - Harmer, H.R., Inc. 1962, 1963 (International Stamp Auctioneers)
  - Hoover, Herbert Clark 1954
  - Inzer, J.C. 1945
  - Karagosian, Sonia 1944
  - New York Police Commission 1941
  - Nichols, Lola
  - O'Hara, Mrs. Edwin J.
  - Porter, William N. (Colonel) 1941
  - Republican National Committee 1964
  - Roemer, L.E. (Major) 1941
  - Royal Canadian Institute 1939
  - Shilstone, Cecil M. (Captain) 1944
  - Silvester, L. Mcd. (Major General) 1942
  - Somervell, Brehon 1945
  - Souren, Y. 1944
  - Treasury Department. Office of Customs. 1955
  - U.S. Army. Finance Center. Retired Pay Division. 1964
  - War Department 1942
  - Watson, Edwin M. 1944
  - Williams, Charles (Lt. Colonel) 1941
  - Willkie, Wendell L. 1943
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and memoranda
- Subject File, 1905-1966. (Box Box No. 1 -3.)
  Reports, military documents, notes, printed matter, and other miscellaneous materials, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Application for federal employment (Box 1.)
  - Camp Robinson, Arkansas. Replacement Training Center - Instructor's Handbook 1943
  - Camp Sibert, Alabama
  - Financial statements - bills, checks, invoices, etc.
  - Furlough Book, U.S.M.A. 1911
  - Home Defense Guide 1942
  - Maps
  - Medals (Box 2.)
  - Omar Khayyam by Darvish of Tehran
  - Our Boys
  - Sixth U.S. Army - Retired Army Officers Rosters 1963, 1964, 1966
  - Special Orders 1946
  - Speech of General George S. Patton Jr. to his 3rd Army on the Eve of the Normandy Invasion
  - The Suckers Club 1934
  - Trainee Tribune. Edgewood Arsenal, Md. March 20, 1942
  - The Traveller's Insurance Company
  - Travelling Itinerary
  - Treasury Department. Office of Collecter of Customs. 1955
  - Uniform Insignia
  - U.S. Military Academy 1958
  - U.S. Post Office - Commemorative Stamp Book 1955
  - Yale University - Sheffield Scientific School 1905 (Box 3.)
- Speeches, 1942-1943. (Box Box No. 3.)
  Speeches arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Address by Brigadier General Haig Shekerjian Bestowing Army-Navy Production Award to Lempco Products, Inc., Bedford, Ohio. December 14, 1942 (Box 3.)
  - Honor Speech, Bain 1943
  - Miscellaneous speech materials
- Miscellaneous. (Box Box No. 3 -4.)
  Clipping file, medals, and memorabilia.
  - Medals (Box 3.)
    - Campaign and Service Medals
    - American Defense Medal
    - American Theater of Operations Medal
    - European, African and Middle Eastern Theater Campaign Medal
    - Asiatic-Pacific Theater Campaign Medal
    - Victory Medal, WWII (Box 3.)
    - Mexican Service Medal (Number 13818) (for service in Mexico against Pancho Villa)
    - Victory Medal, WWI
    - Decorations
    - Legion of Merit (named)
    - Army Commendation Medal (named)
  - Memorabilia (Box 4.)
  - Clippings (Box 4.)